"[She has] a solid understanding of the importance we place on senior officers being able to influence decisions at the operational and strategic level."

Brigadier-General Wynnyk, LFWA Commander

Executive Leader and Manager Infrastructure Management/ Business Planning/ Performance Management

QUALIFICATIONS PROFILE

Energetic, passionate and bilingual executive level leader and manager with 25+ years of experience demonstrating solid achievements in the fields of leadership, infrastructure management and structure optimization in a governmental environment. Utilizes an interactive leadership style and common sense approach to achieve efficiencies and concrete results. A strong and confident leader capable of translating strategic intent into directional goals and deliverables; motivates teams to improve through innovation and active participation. Focused, with a flair for de-conflicting competing priorities, responding to challenges with determination and most importantly, championing changes with positive results.

- Strategic Planning
- Policies and Procedures
- Human Resource (HR) Management
- Project & Program Management
- Environmental Management
- Risk Assessment and Management
- Critical Thinking and Analysis
- Structure Optimization
- Business Planning
- Performance Measurement
- Negotiation and Networking
- Contract Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GOVERNMENT OF ALBERTA – ALBERTA TRANSPORTATION Assistant Deputy Minister Delivery Services Division

2014-present

Along with an exceptional team of professionals, leading the planning, programming and delivery of \$2B of capital provincial highway projects and the management of highway maintenance and rehabilitation throughout the province. Also responsible for the management of municipal transportation grants such as GreenTRIP (Green Transit Incentives Program) and water/wastewater programs and transport engineering services such as permitting, weights and dimensions of loads, and the management of Alberta's high load corridor. The driving and influencing factors to ensure positive success:

- Political environment balancing the needs of the network; new government & officials
- Economic realities solid prioritization of the needs and the essential hwy ervices
- Stakeholders: establishing stellar relationships to ensure collaboration/synchronization
- Trust and education Sustained and focused effort, staff but also Albertans and elected officials

ASSOCIATION OF PROFESSIONAL ENGINEERS AND GEOSCIENTISTS OF ALBERTA (APEGA) – Operations Officer 2013-2014

Worked with a professional, ethical and great team to assist in coordinating some activities within the Association such as synchronizing priorities, creating and implementing training for various staff and scheduling.

This employment provided me with great experience and insights on the crucial importance of the Association and its Governance: the Council and executive Committee, the various and robust Boards, Committees and Representatives that support the overall mandate of the Association and the leadership role it plays among other equivalent jurisdiction associations in Canada.

CANADIAN FORCES, CANADIAN MILITARY ENGINEER

1984-2013

Senior Western Engineer - Area Engineer Officer (Regional Engineer VP)

Land Force Western Area (LFWA) Headquarters, Edmonton, AB

2009-2013

Responsible to oversee, manage and advise on all Army Engineering matters (Operations; Training; HR; Range and Training Areas; Real Property and Project Management; Budgeting and Business Planning) for LFWA (provinces of BC, AB, SK, MB and Northern Territories). Includes the monitoring of an annual budget of \$120M, 1500 facilities (\$3B) and 600 military and public servants. Extensive synchronization and networking are also required with other departments (PWGSC, Natural Resources Canada, Environment Canada), outside agencies such as provinces, municipalities and counties.

- Analysed and provided crucial facts regarding the complexity and uniqueness of LFWA; strategic management now allocates according to the unique time-space-tasks-resources requirements within LFWA (4 time zones, 72% or 300 Hectares of Range and Training Area, 33% of Army Infrastructure or \$3B)
- Optimized essential/mandated Maintenance and Repairs (M&R) activities with Civilian Construction Work Force capacities; identified deficiencies and proposed solutions to Senior Army /CF Strategic level management which resulted in additional allocation of \$4M for LFWA in civilian funding. Standardization of processes (regulations and legislations) to ensure public safety
- Harmonized Civilian Construction Work Force structures across six major CF Bases (600 pers), which resulted in more efficient delivery of essential/mandated M&R activities
- Succeeded in re-instating (with added efficiencies) the preparation and development of capital projects Prioritization of Recapitalization projects at the Army Strategic level (yearly program \$200M) which resulted in an increased investment of \$130M in LFWA from \$21M to \$150M over a five-year program

Joint Command and Staff Programme (JCSP) Canadian Forces College, Toronto, ON

2008-2009

The aim of the Joint Command and Staff Programme (JCSP) is to prepare <u>selected senior</u> officers of the Defence Team for command and staff appointments in the contemporary operating environment across the continuum of operations in national and international settings. The programme focuses on leadership and management development, improves and enhances in-depth strategic planning and problem-solving skills, and further advances team-work, negotiation and communications skills (both in oral and written) in order to be able to perform in a multi-national headquarters or working environment. Emphasis is placed on the following themes or programme goals:

- Command, Leadership and Ethics; Communications Skills; Military Operations Planning; Component Capabilities (understanding of component capabilities such as Army, Navy and Air Force) in military operations; National Security and Defence Studies
- Obtained Master Degree in Defence Studies (MDS) from Canadian Force College.

Joint Engineer Officer, Second in Command Canadian Expeditionary Forces Command Headquarters, Ottawa, ON

2006-2008

This senior staff assignment addressed the HR, material, equipment, infrastructure related to deployed forces overseas (Afghanistan, Democratic Republic Congo, Haiti, etc) dealing with different level of Military Headquarters/organization and OGDs (DFAIT, CIDA and PWGSC).

- Supported the establishment and development of the Construction Management Team, an organization that implemented crucial infrastructure projects in Afghanistan
- Challenged the peace-time Governmental Project Approval Process and succeeded in significantly accelerating the process for essential infrastructure projects for high tempo overseas operations (60 vice 365days)

Business Planning (BP) and Performance Measurement Officer Land Forces Doctrines and Training System, Kingston, ON

2003-2005

Responsible for the business and resources planning, for Army Individual and Collective training. Preparation of a comprehensive Business Plan encompassing \$320M, 1000-pers training cadre and 10,000 trainees while establishing the BP requirements for a \$250M new Training Centre. Development of a Performance Measure Framework with key indicators to properly analyse the trends of Army Training.

- Simplified the Business Planning process by producing a BP cycle with specific timelines and required outputs which resulted in clear and concise plan with annual budgets of \$350M
- Developed strong BP briefings and presentations based on a resource to task approach, underlining associated risks and recommended options which was successful in obtaining a \$15M increase to support Individual Training

CFB Edmonton Senior Engineer Officer (General Manager) Canadian Forces Base Edmonton, Edmonton, AB

1999-2001

Responsible for the Infrastructure and facility management of CFB Edmonton, \$35M budget, 175 employees, 300 building and related works.

- Successfully increased morale following a major CF Wide work force adjustment (20%) by injecting realistic Vacancy Management goals, focused training and work force succession planning
- Risk managed and achieved an on-budget year end closure during a two year period where the cost of electrical and natural gas commodities were significantly fluctuating by identifying key on and off opportunities

Construction Troop Commander and Adjutant (Administration Officer), 1 Combat Engineer Regiment, Edmonton, AB

1995-1999

Responsible for the personnel administration of 300 soldiers.

- Domestic Operations: Winnipeg Floods MB, QC/ON Ice Storm, Salmon Arms Forest Fire
- Bosnia: Initial development of 300 man camp DRVAR, 40-man component leader
- Moved 300 man-unit from CFB Chilliwack to CFB to Edmonton

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- APEGA or Association of Professional Engineers and Geoscientists of Alberta
 - Defence Resources Management Course Ottawa ON, 2010
- •Financial Management for Commanding Officers and Senior Officers Edmonton AB, 2010
 - Master's Degree, Joint Command and Staff Course, Canadian Forces College (Masters Graduating Paper "Detainees" was referred to in National Post, Fall of 2009)

 Toronto ON, 2009
- •Land Force Command and Staff Course (Leadership, Operations and Resources Planning) Army College Kingston, 1999
 - •Bachelor of Engineering (Civil), McGill University Montreal, 1989
 - Finance Management and Accounting System Performance Measurement Training
 - Conflict Resolution Harassment Advisor and Instructor
 - Managing Civilian in the work Place Course
 - Canadian School of Public Service Employee Management Ethical Training

COMMUNITY INVOLVEMENT

- École La Mission, Société des Parents, Trésorière, St. Albert AB 2009 to Present
 - École La Découverte, Société des Parents, Conseillère, Orléans ON 2006
- École Madeleine de Roybon, Société des Parents, Conseillère and Spokesperson for the construction of a new school facility, Kingston ON 2004
- Edmonton Garrison Climbing Club, Edmonton Garrison Gymnasium, President (organized and coordinated the stand-up of the club), Edmonton AB 1997 to 2000